export const chapter = "Chapter - 6: Balanced Diet ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question: "What is the term for all the food consumed in a day?",
          optionA: "Nutrition",
          optionB: "Diet",
          optionC: "Nutrients",
          correctAnswer: "Diet",
        },
        {
          question: "How many main nutrients are included in a balanced diet?",
          optionA: "Four",
          optionB: "Five",
          optionC: "Six",
          correctAnswer: "Six",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which nutrient is required for body growth and cell repair?",
          optionA: "Carbohydrates",
          optionB: "Proteins",
          optionC: "Fats",
          correctAnswer: "Proteins",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the role of carbohydrates in the body?",
          optionA: "Strengthening bones",
          optionB: "Source of energy",
          optionC: "Required for eyes and skin",
          correctAnswer: "Source of energy",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the foundation of good health and well-being?",
          optionA: "Balanced Diet",
          optionB: "Regular Exercise",
          optionC: "Medication",
          correctAnswer: "Balanced Diet",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which food group includes products like white rice, cookies, and cakes?",
          optionA: "Fruits",
          optionB: "Grains",
          optionC: "Meat and Non-vegetarian products",
          correctAnswer: "Grains",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the main role of vegetables in a balanced diet?",
          optionA: "Source of energy",
          optionB: "Body growth",
          optionC: "Provide natural nutrients",
          correctAnswer: "Provide natural nutrients",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which food group is low in nutritional level and high in calories?",
          optionA: "Fats, Sugar, and Oils",
          optionB: "Milk and Dairy Products",
          optionC: "Meat and Non-vegetarian products",
          correctAnswer: "Fats, Sugar, and Oils",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What do milk and dairy products provide in addition to proteins and calcium?",
          optionA: "Vitamin C",
          optionB: "Vitamin D, potassium, vitamin B12, etc.",
          optionC: "Iron and Zinc",
          correctAnswer: "Vitamin D, potassium, vitamin B12, etc.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Where do proteins, iron, and zinc primarily come from in a balanced diet?",
          optionA: "Fruits",
          optionB: "Vegetables",
          optionC: "Meat, Fish, and Non-vegetarian products",
          correctAnswer: "Meat, Fish, and Non-vegetarian products",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "To keep ourselves fit and healthy, we should be careful about what type of ________ we are eating.",
          optionA: "Exercise",
          optionB: "Sleep",
          optionC: "Food",
          correctAnswer: "Food",
        },
        {
          question:
            "A ________ diet includes six main nutrients: fats, proteins, carbohydrates, fibres, vitamins, and minerals.",
          optionA: "Healthy",
          optionB: "Balanced",
          optionC: "Vegetarian",
          correctAnswer: "Balanced",
        },
        {
          question: "Carbohydrates are the primary source of ________.",
          optionA: "Protein",
          optionB: "Energy",
          optionC: "Vitamins",
          correctAnswer: "Energy",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Proteins are essential for body growth and ________ repair.",
          optionA: "Muscle",
          optionB: "Cell",
          optionC: "Bone",
          correctAnswer: "Cell",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Fats, in addition to proteins, serve as a source of ________.",
          optionA: "Calcium",
          optionB: "Energy",
          optionC: "Vitamins",
          correctAnswer: "Energy",
        },
        {
          question:
            "A balanced diet is crucial for maintaining good ________ health.",
          optionA: "Physical",
          optionB: "Mental",
          optionC: "Emotional",
          correctAnswer: "Mental",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Grains, vegetables, fruits, fats, sugar and oils, milk and dairy products, and meat, fish, and non-vegetarian products are the six basic ________ groups.",
          optionA: "Nutrient",
          optionB: "Exercise",
          optionC: "Food",
          correctAnswer: "Food",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Whole grains, such as whole wheat products, oatmeal, and popcorn, are high in ________ and fibres.",
          optionA: "Calories",
          optionB: "Nutrients",
          optionC: "Sugar",
          correctAnswer: "Nutrients",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Vegetables have hundreds of natural nutrients, including ________, minerals, and dietary fibres.",
          optionA: "Fats",
          optionB: "Vitamins",
          optionC: "Proteins",
          correctAnswer: "Vitamins",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Milk and dairy products are rich in proteins, vitamins, calcium, vitamin D, potassium, and ________.",
          optionA: "Vitamin C",
          optionB: "Iron",
          optionC: "Vitamin B12",
          correctAnswer: "Vitamin B12",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "A balanced diet includes five main nutrients: fats, proteins, carbohydrates, fibres, vitamins, and minerals.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Carbohydrates are the primary source of energy for the body.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Proteins are not essential for body growth and cell repair.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question: "Fats serve as a low-calorie source of energy in the body.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "A balanced diet is crucial only for physical health, not mental health.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Vegetables are high in natural nutrients such as vitamins, minerals, and dietary fibres.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Whole grains, like whole wheat products, are low in nutrients and fibres.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question: "Milk and dairy products are not a good source of calcium.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Bengal Tiger was declared the National Animal of India in 1973.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The lotus flower, the National Flower of India, symbolizes wealth and prosperity.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
